Privacy Policy, all products, for Parents
=========================================

### [Back to Wordshark](https://www.wordshark.co.uk/)    [Back to Numbershark](https://www.wordshark.co.uk/numbershark/)

White Space Ltd Privacy Policy for Wordshark Online and for non-online products – for parents  
Last Updated: 02/02/2023
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

KEY DATA PROTECTION FACT;  
● Our ICO (Information Commission Office) registration number is ZA475290. ● For queries relating to data protection, your contact is Ruth Savery, Company Director at White Space Ltd.  
White Space Ltd Products: ● Wordshark Online ● Wordshark v5 ● Numbershark v5  
A user purchasing, trialling or using a complimentary subscription to Wordshark Online will be deemed to be a subscribing customer.  
The details of this policy may vary from time to time as we seek ever more ways to improve our security. We may ● Change where your data is stored ● Change what types of personal data we store ● Make a change to a third party data processor  
These will be reflected by changes on this page and the administrator for Wordshark Online accounts will be notified by email. You can see when this Privacy Policy was last updated by checking the updated date displayed at the top of this Privacy Policy.  
What do we collect?  
To enable us to provide you with the products you subscribe to and to communicate with you, we request, store and process specific personal data relating to you. It is impractical in most circumstances for you to remain anonymous, and we may not be able to  
interact with you, provide access to any of the products or answer any enquiry if we are not able to identify you or collect your personal information. We will obtain this directly from you, when you sign up, and when you interact with us through phone, email or otherwise. This includes information that you provide when you register an account/ purchase a product with us direct or via a reseller agent, renew, use our services, enter a competition or survey, subscribe to marketing communications from us, and/or submit enquiries to us. We may use your personal data to market similar products and services to you, which is a legitimate business interest of ours.  
You can however withdraw your consent to receive marketing material at any time by contacting us at online@wordshark.co.uk or telephoning: 020 8748 5927.  
The information that we collect, and the use to which it is put  
We collect the following personal data from you: • Name • Contact telephone number • Email address • Address  
This information is used for the purposes of the fulfilment of our contract with you – we use it to set up an account for you, to bill you, to manage your account and provide customer support. Without this information, we would be unable to provide you with the product.  
For Wordshark Online the following apply • We also collect the first name and surname of the child or children that you are registering to use the product. This is for the purpose of setting up the account and fulfilling our contractual obligations to you.  
• You have the option of providing us with the child’s email address. This will be used for the purpose of setting up their account but is not required in order for us to do this.  
• Where you have subscribed to a free trial or are a complimentary user, we will use the information provided to contact you at the end of the trial to market the paid for versions. This is a legitimate business interest of ours.  
We also collect and hold your information to market our services to you, though you have the option to withdraw your consent for these. These are legitimate business interests of ours, and you can opt out of this communication at any time.  
We may also use your information if we need to seek professional advice.  
There will also be cases where we have a legal obligation to provide information (such as to HMRC or to the police), and we will comply with our legal and regulatory obligations as and when they arise.  
Who do we share your data with  
We do not sell users’ personal data to external 3rd parties. We may, however, use specific 3rd party processors that are;  
● Contracted to enable us to carry out our obligations arising from the terms and conditions entered into with our customers. ● To assist with business processes such as accounting services and customer support. ● Providing marketing services such as email, telemarketing and direct mail campaigns.  
Finally, as explained above, we may be required to disclose your personal data to competent law enforcement and regulatory bodies, or with other third parties to enable us to meet our legal and regulatory requirements.  
Our third-party processors for Wordshark Online  
Company Purpose 1 Amazon Web Services, inc. Data hosting and storage is in the UK 2 Zoho Corporation Accounting software, subscription management software, customer relationship management and bulk email broadcasting system (for the distributions of email newsletters and promotions – EU 3 Infostretch UK Ltd Website and software development services – UK company with team in India 4 Buckhill Server maintenance and IT related services – UK company with team in EU 5 TechEdology Product development services and marketing consultancy – UK  
6 Martin Newman IT and software development related consultancy services – UK 7 Try Catch Software  
DevOps Consultancy services  
For all other products, only lines 2, 5 and 6 in the above table apply  
Security  
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect and store.  
All data is encrypted at rest and in transit using industry standards.  
How do we your store data and for how long We store your data within the UK . When we need to send personal data outside of the UK, we ensure safeguards are in place for the third party data processor to provide the same level of protection for personal data as there is in the UK. We can provide you with details about where we are sending your personal data.  
If you have any questions about the safeguards that are in place please contact Ruth Savery.  
We will only keep data whilst we have a legitimate reason to. Otherwise the data will be deleted. For example if you terminate your Wordshark Online subscription or it lapses, any personal data is held for 12 months. Otherwise after this period, data relating to your users will be automatically deleted from the relevant product platform.  
Your contact details will be retained on our customer relationship management system and email system, to make it easy to re-activate your account should you change your mind and to continue receiving product newsletters and marketing updates, and you can opt out of this communication at any time.  
We do reserve the right to retain and use personal data where required to comply with legal obligations, to resolve disputes, and/ or to enforce our terms and conditions.  
Cookie Policy  
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you  
agree, the file is added, and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. We will not store personal data. We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and to improve our website by tailoring it according to customer needs.  
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.  
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. However, this may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.  
Controlling your personal information  
The UK GDPR provides the following rights for individuals whose personal data is processed: 1. The right to be informed 2. The right of access 3. The right to rectification 4. The right to erasure 5. The right to restrict processing 6. The right to data portability 7. The right to object to processing 8. Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling. (We do not carry out automated decision making and profiling)  
To request amendment or deletion of information relating to you, simply email or write to us using the contact details provided in the ‘How to contact us’ heading below, instructing us on the data that needs to be changed or deleted.  
We will then immediately delete your personal data unless there is a legal reason why we need to keep your personal data. In that circumstance we will let you know and destroy your personal information  
as soon as we are legally entitled to do so. On a regular basis we send product update news via email. All recipients have the right to opt out or unsubscribe from this communication by clicking on the unsubscribe link. Alternatively, recipients can email us to opt out of receiving further newsletters.  
Right to lodge a complaint with the Supervising Authority If you have any concerns or complaints about how we use your personal data we hope you will alert us to these directly (see the Contact information below). In any event you are entitled to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) which is the supervisory authority in the UK. Their contact details and the procedure can be found at www.ico.gov.uk  
How to contact us  
If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your personal information, please email: online@wordshark.co.uk or write to White Space Ltd, 1 Lochaline Street, London W6 9SJ.

Discover more

Wordshark

Numbershark

Follow us!

Copyright Wordshark 2023  [Terms & Conditions](https://www.wordshark.co.uk/terms-conditions/)[Data Processing Terms, Privacy Policy, Modern Slavery, Cookies](https://wolhelp.wordshark.co.uk/portal/en/kb/articles/privacy-policy)

We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site we will assume that you are happy with it.[Ok](#)[Privacy policy](https://wolhelp.wordshark.co.uk/portal/en/kb/articles/privacy-policy)
